Privacy Statement                              

**[United Way  
of Greater Milwaukee  
& Waukesha County](https://unitedwaygmwc.org/unitedwaymilwaukee-NEW.htm)**

Menu  

        * [Teen Mental Wellness: Empowering Minds Sustaining & Inaugural Donors](https://unitedwaygmwc.org/Empowering-Minds-Sustaining-and-Inaugural-Donors)
        * [Reducing Barriers to Employment & Advancement: Dominiquia & Next Door](https://unitedwaygmwc.org/Stories/Reducing-Barriers-to-Employment-Advancement-Dominiquia)

[site search](javascript:void(0))

Privacy Statement
=================

* Privacy Statement

Main Content

**United Way of Greater Milwaukee & Waukesha County PRIVACY STATEMENT**

**Last reviewed/updated:** September 23, 2024

**Purpose of this Privacy Statement** 

In an effort to improve your experience interacting digitally with United Way of Greater Milwaukee & Waukesha County (UWGMWC) and to improve the quality of information you receive from UWGMWC, we collect information as you interact with our website, email messages, social media posts, etc.  The details below are intended to share what information we collect and how we use that information.  

**We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization other than contractors or service providers needed to complete your UWGMWC transactions or improve our ability to communicate effectively with you.** 

**Your pledge information is known only to you, UWGMWC, and, to the extent necessary, contractors or service providers needed to complete your transaction, or volunteer solicitors or volunteers at your company responsible for conducting your workplace campaign.** 

UWGMWC takes your privacy very seriously and cares about how your information is collected, used, and shared.  We are providing this Privacy Statement to explain our practices and the choices that you can make about the way your information is used by UWGMWC. The Privacy Statement describes our practices in connection with the information we collect through websites operated by us or our service providers (the “**Websites**”), through the software applications made available by us for use on or through computers and mobile devices (the “**Apps**”), through our social media pages that we control through which you are accessing this Privacy Statement (collectively, our “**Social Media Pages**”), through HTML-formatted email messages that we send to you that link to this Privacy Statement, and through offline interactions that we may have with you (including the Websites, the Apps, and our Social Media Pages: the “**Services**”).  

By providing Personal Information to UWGMWC, taking surveys, answering questions, etc. you agree to this Privacy Statement.  

**Personal Information We May Collect** 

UWGMWC may collect Personal Information including name, email address, postal address, phone number, social media ID, **and** similar contact information and credit card or other payment information. If you choose to provide your payment or credit card information to UWGMWC for pledge or gift purposes, we will only use that information for the purposes for which it was provided.   

**Information About Minors** 

The Site is not intended for persons under the age of 16. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information online from persons in this age group. We reserve the right to delete any information identified as having been provided by such persons at our discretion. 

**How We May Collect Personal Information** 

UWGMWC and our service providers may collect Personal Information in a variety of ways, including but not limited to Personal Information you provide to us through online and offline forms such as e-newsletters, surveys, donation forms, event registration/participation (including volunteering), and interaction with email and websites including responding to questions or taking surveys.  

**How UWGMWC Uses Personal Information** 

UWGMWC and our service providers may use Personal Information to:  

* Send you information regarding UWGMWC, our affiliates, and our partners.  
* Process and respond to inquiries for which you provided the information, such as to process donations, register or renew as a donor or supporter, or receive information about a project, special event, and volunteer activity. 
* Personalize the content, improve the navigability of the Services, and customize your experience on the Services, including targeted content, customized volunteer opportunities, and/or customized email messages.  
* Notify you about special programs, events, and volunteer opportunities.  

**Cookies and Other Information We May Collect**  

Cookies: Like many companies, our Site may use “cookies” to help make sure the Site is meeting the needs of its users and to help us make improvements. Cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer’s hard drive when you visit certain websites.  We may use cookies set by us on the Site to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor.  We use third-party cookies set by our service provider, Google Analytics, to collect information about how visitors use the Site, including how long you spend on each page, and how you got to the Site.  We do not allow Google to use or share our analytics data.   

 Other Information: Any information that does not reveal your specific identity or does not directly relate to an identifiable individual.  We may collect Other Information such as IP address, browser type, mobile device type, content visited while on the Websites or Apps, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, Internet browser type and version, or the duration of the use of the Services. Collecting browser activities or IP addresses, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited, are common practices and are often performed automatically by many websites, applications and other services for such purposes as calculating usage levels, helping diagnose server problems, and administering the Services.   

**How You Can Control Collection and Use of Your Information** 

**Marketing Email Opt Out:** You may, at any time, choose to opt out of receiving emails sent by UWGMWC by following the opt-out procedures at the bottom of our emails. Please allow 10 business days for us to respond to your request. 

**Accessing, Modifying, Updating, and Deleting Your Information:** We strive to keep our records as accurate as possible. You may, under applicable laws, have a right to access, correct, modify, or request the deletion of your Personal Information that you have previously provided to us at any time.  To do so, please call us at (414) 263-8100 and ask for the VP of Digital Innovation or [contact us online](https://unitedwaygmwc.org/Contact-Us). 

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting a change or deletion (e.g., when you make a donation or enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the Personal Information provided until after the completion of such donation or promotion). There may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed.  

**How We Protect Information** 

UWGMWC uses appropriate and reasonable organizational, electronic, procedural, physical, administrative, and technical measures to help safeguard Personal Information from unauthorized access or disclosure. We use industry standard security controls (such as firewalls) and protocols (such as SSL/TLS). We protect the security of credit card transactions by using third-party PCI Compliant credit card processors for the storage and encryption of credit card data. Access to personally identifiable information is restricted and password protected; only employees who need the information to perform a specific purpose are granted access. We take these and other appropriate precautions to help ensure the security, integrity, and confidentiality of customer information; however, no transmission or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your use of the Services or engagement with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us as described in the “**Questions/Contact Information**” section below.  

**Retention Period** 

We will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Statement unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.   

**VoterVoice App**

VoterVoice is a platform used by United Way for web visitors to optionally provide contact information for the purpose of participating in education and advocacy campaigns. Information collected on the Voter Voice platform will be shared with United Way of Greater Milwaukee & Waukesha County and its affiliates (as applicable) for the purposes of facilitating and coordinating the campaign and for engaging with the respective local United Way.

The VoterVoice Privacy Statement is available [here.](https://fiscalnote.com/privacy?_gl=1*1k2n9x4*_gcl_au*MTQ4NDI1NDQ3NS4xNzI2MTkwNTU2&_ga=2.266754766.1592889488.1726190556-1086451754.1726190556)

**Third Party Content and Links** 

Our Services may contain links to third-party websites, applications, or similar technology that are not associated with or over which UWGMWC has no control. Any access to and use of such linked websites is not governed by this Statement but instead is governed by the privacy statements of those third party websites. UWGMWC is not responsible for the information practices or content of these other websites and/or applications.  

**Changes to this Privacy Statement**  

UWGMWC may, from time to time, amend this Privacy Statement. We will post any revisions to the Services, and we advise you to check back periodically. The “Last Updated” reference at the top of this page indicates when this Privacy Statement was last revised. Any changes to this Privacy Statement become effective when the revised Privacy Statement on the Services is posted. Your continued use of the Services or engagement in the Interactions after such changes are implemented will also constitute your affirmative consent to the revised Privacy Statement.  

**Questions/Contact Information** 

If you have any questions, concerns, or suggestions regarding this Privacy Statement or UWGMWC’s privacy practices, you may [contact us online](https://unitedwaygmwc.org/Contact-Us) or call us at (414) 263- 8100 and ask for the VP of Digital Innovation Monday through Friday between 8:00am and 4:30pm Central Time. 

Because email communications are not always secure, please do not include credit card or other sensitive information in your emails to UWGMWC. 

© 2024 United Way of Greater Milwaukee & Waukesha County is a 501(C)(3) Nonprofit registered in the US under EIN: 39-0806190.

This site is powered by the Northwoods Titan Content Management System.
